Sync & corrections by Blue-Bird™
Subtitle translation by Ju-young Park
Modify by Blue-Bird™
ORIGINAL STORY SWEET HOME
BY CARNBY KIM AND YOUNGCHAN HWANG
You died when you should have lived,
and I lived when I should have died.
I'm scared
and nervous.
I know it's crazy to say
something like this in this situation,
but I think I should say it.
I like you, Ji-su.
Is that
God's will, too?
No.
It's my will.
Here.
You were always ugly,
but you look way uglier now.
You want to live, right?
Just act like before.
Nothing good will happen
if you're near me.
Get away from me if you want to live.
My bad luck will rub off on you.
Jeez.
You really hate yourself, don't you?
Everyone around me dies.
Whether they kill themselves…
or get killed by monsters…
Are you throwing a pity party?
Well, I have really bad luck too.
You know I'm an orphan, right?
My family went to see
a ballet performance one day,
and we got into an accident.
So both my mom and dad…
My dad said he was tired,
but I was stubborn about going there.
I made Eun-hyeok become an orphan, too.
And I ruined Eun-hyeok's life.
We're not blood-related at all.
And honestly, we're not even family
without our parents.
But he took a leave from school
to help me study ballet.
He's crazy. He's really crazy.
He said it wasn't my fault.
He said it's okay.
Does he think I'll be okay with it
just because he is?
I didn't want to be indebted to him,
so I was determined to become a successful
ballerina to pay him back later, but…
Damn it.
My ankle's so ruined
I can't even do a turn.
What do you think?
Am I pitiful?
You seem to think
your life is most pitiful,
but it's not.
I'll prove it to you.
I'm going to survive with you
until the end.
I had nothing else to do anyway.
Don't try to make yourself miserable.
Things are bad enough already.
It's been about 30 years.
I grabbed a knife
at my first birthday ceremony.
JUNG JAE-HEON
Jung Jae-heon…
Drink as much as you want.
Just five more days.
I endured 30 hard years.
Five days is nothing.
We should find him.
Burn them.
Let me ask you a favor.
There's something inside this building.
-We must find it.
-Find what?
I don't know. An underground tunnel
or a bunker or something.
What do you plan to do?
Hide.
More people will die
if we keep fighting the monsters.
Young people who have their whole lives
ahead of them are dying out.
I believe that you'll survive this.
I can tell from your face.
Grandpa, look.
Is the army coming to rescue us?
Are they?
Move on your own.
-I'll greet the guests.
-What?
You can't trust soldiers
in such situations.
I guess you might not know.
I know it, too.
You have a junior colleague now.
She's going to be a secret agent, too.
It's coming this way!
Damn it, this is bad. It's coming!
Have you been well?
-Hold him.
-Help!
-Stop!
-Okay, one, two…
It's not opening.
We failed again?
Find everyone who's hiding.
It'll be easier to just shoot them.
You always talk about killing everyone.
We should have fun with them.
A robbery in the middle of the day?
Didn't your mother buy you any paper?
Why the hell did you scribble
on your face?
You stupid old geezer.
You've lived enough.
Why are you still alive?
-It's not even a good world to live in.
-Goodness.
What kind of losers just intruded and--
Say one more word,
and I'll tear your jaw off.
Your mission
is to stay hidden.
You have to stay in there.
Don't ever get caught.
You can do that, right?
But…
What about Yeong-su? Where is--
It's okay. Everything will be fine.
I think it's a bit bigger than last time.
Should I measure the area every time?
This is your jail now.
-No!
-Ji-eun!
I'm scared.
-Oh, my legs hurt.
-Mr. Han…
Mr. Han.
No, Mr. Han! You'll be killed, too!
What do you think you're doing?
Come and take her.
How could you kill her?
People's lives are useless these days.
You're so emotional.
Are you going to cry
over every person's death?
Mister, you crossed the line. Go inside.
Mr. Han!
You can all live harmoniously in there.
You just have
a little less room than before.
Damn, they started already.
I missed the good part.
Jeez.
Hey.
Where are you going?
You stink right now. A lot.
You shit…
It's a girl.
A girl.
She's hurt.
That's enough.
Get lost.
Jung-seop is looking for you.
Stop calling him by his name, you shit!
It's really not the time to do that.
You could be killed
by Jung-seop.
I'm Shin Jung-seop.
Let's all get along without fighting.
How can you say that after what you did?
How can you treat people like this?
Do you think we're beasts?
This is all I've seen and learned.
If you all do as I say,
I won't kill anyone else.
So?
What are you planning to do?
We should get to know each other.
I bet you're curious about us, too.
Then tell us.
Where were you before coming here?
What happened there?
They all died.
Did they die?
Or did you kill them?
It was a small church.
They'd had it fortified well,
so I got my hopes up,
but all of them were already dead.
What's interesting is
that there weren't any signs
of a monster being there.
They had all killed each other.
It's not the time to be worrying
about monsters.
Humans…
are the scariest.
What is it?
What?
Ui-myeong said you were looking for me.
What? No, I wasn't.
You son of a bitch!
Did you find anything?
A girl.
She's hurt.
Hey, stop frowning.
These people are already scared.
You just left her alone?
Why? Was she not your type?
Should I kill her?
Don't touch her. I'm saving her for later.
Are you crazy? Stop standing up to them.
Do you want to get yourself killed?
I did it because I wanted to live.
-We have to wait.
-Until when?
It seems they're criminals who killed
soldiers and stole their weapons.
And they only have a few guns
when there are dozens
of monsters out there.
But we can't just do nothing.
There will be an opportunity.
I'm sure of it.
You're not the only weapon we have.
SAFETY ON
Hey.
You don't know how to use that, do you?
No, I didn't serve in the military.
You asshole…
You said you were a firefighter.
I used to be in the special forces.
How did you find the rifle?
I saw you hiding it.
You really made an effort.
Who's the leader here?
Who made this?
I did.
I heard someone even performed
surgery in here. Who did that?
I did.
Everyone here is completely useless.
There's an old man and a cripple,
and even a patient.
This place is the worst so far,
but quite a lot of people survived here.
You're young,
but I guess you're pretty capable.
I like you. What do you say?
Will you abandon them and join me?
Or will you…
just die?
Hey…
What…
You made a good choice.
You're pretty smart.
Sir!
There's a monster here.
Yi-kyung.
Mister.
Come here.
Why did you go in there?
Well, my mission was to hide,
but I saw Yi-kyung.
She's a secret agent, too…
and Grandpa wasn't coming. I was scared.
Don't!
It saved me!
She might not be dangerous.
She's still human.
-There are monsters that don't harm--
-So?
She's going to be a monster anyway.
But…
You locked her up because you were scared.
You're such a hypocrite.
I thought you were pretty smart,
but you're just a kid.
I'm Shin Jung-seop.
I want you to know
that it's nothing personal.
Do you have any final words to say?
-You asshole!
-Hey!
Oh, come on.
You're the toughest
among all the losers here.
Watch and learn.
What just happened? Who…
Did they kill Eun-hyeok?
He's on their side now.
So it must be Seon-yeong.
They're different from you.
They could all get killed.
Hyun-su…
There will be an opportunity.
I'm sure of it.
What are you waiting for?
You're a doctor.
You should declare her dead.
Hypocrisy comes at a huge cost.
If we hesitate any longer,
more people will die.
What's your plan?
You don't know how to use a gun,
but are you good at getting away?
I've usually been the one chasing.
You must be good at it now
because you're not alone.
"I'll get things cleaned up first,
Jung-seop."
He's pretending to be so nice.
Why doesn't he just hold a funeral
for her while he's at it?
Sir, I'm telling you, Ui-myeong
really doesn't suit our group.
Get her!
GREEN SUPERMARKET
What was that?
Cha Hyun-su! Now!
Come on!
Wait!
Close your eyes.
Not you, you shit!
-Get him!
Everyone, stop!
Let them go
before I blow his brains out.
Sir.
No, Ms. An…
I'm sorry…
You're keeping something strange.
Sir, he'll recover soon.
We should kill
every monster.
Jeez.
She's really going to die this time.
Shut up, you idiot.
Where the hell have you been?
Shut your trap. Your breath stinks.
What? That son of a bitch…
You smell of disinfectant.
You'd better go over there.
The patient's in bad condition.
I think she might die soon.
No.
I'm hurt, too.
Do you want to see my wound?
You bitch.
What? Do you want to go first? Good.
Yu-ri…
Hurry.
I knew this would happen!
Drop your gun.
Should we make a bet on who can kill
more people?
The side that's more scared
should surrender!
Drop your gun.
Drop it, you bitch!
This is just the beginning, you bitch!
Damn it!
My goodness…
Wait here.
I…
killed a person.
It's okay.
He wasn't human.
Here.
Let's just burn him.
That's no fun.
Will he die if he falls from here?
No, wait.
Should I take out his intestines?
Or should I cut off his head
and keep it as a souvenir?
-There's no need…
-He's not human anyway.
Well, it doesn't matter even if he is.
Look at him struggling to live.
I won't let
any of you go downstairs.
I see.
You're pretty tough.
But you don't seem
to get the picture here.
I'll kill you slowly,
as many times as you want.
You crossed the line this time, Jung-seop.
Do you want that, too?
No, I don't…
I don't want that.
Thank you.
I like that look on your face.
It's nice to meet you.
SPECIAL INFECTEE REPORT GUIDE
It must hurt.
I know how it feels.
You can never get used to it.
Why did you kill him?
I thought you'd be grateful.
You were on the same side.
How can a wolf and a rabbit
be on the same side?
The rabbit was pretending to be
a wolf, so I just played along.
But there's no need for that now.
It's not a crime for a wolf
to kill a rabbit after playing with it.
That's just natural in this world now.
There are monsters that don't…
harm humans.
Why are you alone?
Where's Hyun-su?
We don't have time for this!
What do you mean?
If they come down, we're all dead!
What are you talking about?
Damn it.
Let's all survive together, okay?
I've never seen such a thing before.
It can't kill anything in this state.
Okay, I can see that there's a monster
that doesn't harm humans.
But will there be humans
that don't harm monsters?
Take a look at this.
"Special Infectee Report Guide.
We guarantee the safety of anyone
who reports a special infectee.
You will be transferred to a safe camp."
-What does that mean?
-They want us to report them.
Do you still think those people
you're trying to protect
will welcome you after reading this?
So what do you think?
Which side will you bet on?
They're coming.
Yeong-su.
BASED ON SWEET HOME
BY CARNBY KIM AND YOUNGCHAN HWANG
Subtitle translation by Ju-young Park